let's start off with asking you do you
work or do you study I work actually um
so I co-founded the startup it's called
secure my scholarship it's an ettech
platform that connects students with
scholarships at universities around the
world so I I work full-time longer than
full-time of you may say what do you
love about your job I love the impact
that we create man uh so we give you
know students that come from hardworking
middleclass families or workingclass
families a chance at going to the
University of their dreams and
personally I love that about what we do
did you always want to do that job this
specifically no but have I always wanted
to work in something that would allow me
to create an impact yes everything I've
ever done in my life has been around
companies with impact or with social
causes and somebody once asked me if I
wasn't with secure my scholarship what
would you do and I said I'd work at a
nonprofit is there anything that you
dislike about your job me personally no
but if you ask my fiance she will tell
you that I my job takes up a lot of my
time and I think she hates that about my
job would you like to do any other job
in the future I got my hands for with
secure my scholarship right now but in
the future who knows you know I mean uh
I love solving problems and helping make
people's lives better um and the world
has a lot of issues so you know who
knows now let's talk about mobile phones
how often do you use your mobile phone
oh I use my mobile phone every day the
company basically runs off my MobileOne
phone what are some of your favorite
apps uh I use LinkedIn a lot um I use a
productivity tool called Asana it allows
me to like track my tasks and manage my
day I use slack a lot uh internal team
communication WhatsApp obviously I mean
everybody uses WhatsApp uh and yeah
couple apps not that many I'm not one of
those guys with
1,500 apps on their phone I have about
eight or nine apps that I use do you
think that you use your phone too much
Times Yes uh you know it's funny that
you asked that uh before secure my
scholarship uh myself and the same
founding team we actually founded a
startup called lock in stock it was a
mobile app that basically rewarded you
with offers and discounts for not using
your phone when you were in class we
wanted to kind of help students pay
attention more in class learn better um
do better in their studies and then when
they were done they could get you know
buy one get one free at the pizza place
or something like that so yeah now let's
talk about your school did you enjoy
school that is a tough question um when
I was in school I hated it but I think
the beauty with school is that the later
in life you go the more you begin to
appreciate the school that you went to
who was your favorite teacher my
favorite
teacher uh my favorite teacher was a was
a woman named Mrs mik Menan uh she she
was my math teacher in grades 10 and 11
and and um I really liked her classes
and I really enjoyed them and what
specifically did you dislike about
school um I went to a school that made
academic performance very very important
everything revolved around okay do
better you got to do better your grades
all of that stuff much to the neglect of
maybe extracurriculars or Sports I
played cricket and football in high
school and I remember we wouldn't have
any training practices any
practice matches we wouldn't do go to
any tournaments or we'd go to very few
tournaments um and I didn't particularly
like that when I was in school the focus
on academics and not really on other
stuff describe a period of time from
your studies that was difficult I'd say
the hardest time during my studies that
was difficult was when I was in
university I think second or third year
of University to go to the university
that I went to it required a lot of
effort I think my parents really saved
to send me to University and I had to
get a bunch of scholarships and all of
that stuff I wanted to make the most of
it but I didn't quite know how to do
that I was majoring in economics but I
also wanted to study this class and this
class and this class and all of that
stuff and really make the most of my
time because I was lucky to be at the
University that I went to um this was
perhaps 2015 2016 second or third year
of University um it was hard because um
I had only a limited amount of time and
had to fit all of this stuff in um but I
think through that experience and I came
out very well through that experience I
learned I think I learned time
management you know just actually
breaking down what I wanted to do how I
wanted to do it I had to schedule out my
day and my week very very very well and
really just make it happen for myself
and that was super difficult right
because uh the school I went to
everything was given to you on a platter
these are your classes this is what you
got to do but at University I had to
basically make my own schedule and if
you were doing a simple major and that
was it then you know no harm no foul
that's very clearcut whatever when I
graduated University I graduated with a
major in economics and minors in
political science international
relations mass communication and
business administration I would have had
another minor in finance as well so I
had four minors that I graduated with
along with my major and I would had a
fifth minor as well um and to make all
of this work and just fit it into my
schedule super difficult but as I said
you know I I was lucky to be a
university when I was and I wanted to
make the most of my time there so we've
been talking about a difficult time you
had at University and we're going to
continue to talk about University
education and higher education in
general should higher education be free
to all
citizens to thank you for watching this
video I want to give you a free course
that has helped thousands of students
improve their I speaking score what it's
going to do is take you through through
every single part of the test and give
you strategies for part one part two and
part three and also allow you to
practice at home for free and get
feedback to sign up for that for free
all you have to do is just click the
link in the description thanks very much
and let's get back to the video in an
Ideal World yes I think the cost of
quality education today is incredibly
expensive and is rising year over-year
um what happens with that is that this
phenomenal then prices out so many
people from the middle class and the
working class who aren't given the same
opportunities it shouldn't be that okay
only if you can afford to pay $150,000 a
year you can go to a top 10 business
school around the world and succeed in
life I mean that's that's not fair it
shouldn't have to be that way um I
through secure my scholarship I remember
there was this one girl two weeks ago
who applied for an MBA in the USA and
the cost of that MBA was like
$65,000 which I mean $65,000 is a lot of
money and especially when you're earning
in rupees in India that's a hell of a
lot of money now I mean what's her
solution I mean should she give up on
her dreams should she not go ahead and
do it I mean what is what does she do
she applied through our platform we
helped her get a
$25,000 scholarship to bring her fees
down from $65,000 to 40,000 we can't
make it free unfortunately we're not the
government we're not God or the
government or whatever we can't make it
free but we can minimize it as much as
we can I remember I was on a call with
her and just the the look of excitement
on her face when she got this because
she was taking a loan to do go do her
MBA and we effectively cut her loan by
half and that's amazing should
scholarships only be given to gifted
children in a world with finite
resources I I suppose I guess this is a
tricky question right because if there
are own
n number of seats and there's a cost
that is why and whatever then you have
to ensure that students who are I guess
U academically talented or talented at a
sporting level or an athletic level or
whatever are able to get that push that
they need because there are only limited
seats so you know if they're not going
to get it then somebody else is going to
get the seat and they're going to miss
out so in that scenario yes scholarships
and when I in this scenar in this sense
I mean 100% scholarships should be given
to gifted children because they've
displayed um some sort of aptitude or
level where they can succeed and they
should be given that push I think now
who determines how scholarships are
given out and I know there's a lot of
Foul Play at the University level or you
know this guy is my cousin's kid so give
him 100% scholarship it shouldn't be
like that there should be an
unbiased uh counsil that has to vote and
decide or however these things are done
but it should be fair but in a world
with limited seats and limited
opportunities I guess you know you have
to make sure that students who are who
display a level of talent get access to
those scholarships I suppose but again
just coming back to the previous
question if if every student was allowed
to study that's a much more Ideal World
I think some people think that Charities
should uh provide gifted children with
scholarships and other people think that
the government should do it who do you
think should provide
scholarships to thank you for making it
this far in the video I want to give you
10% off our VIP course I VIP course is
the most successful I course in the
world that is a fact because we have
more band seven eight and nine success
stories than any other I course in the
entire world we do that by simplifying
the whole is process supporting you with
some of the best is teachers in the
world and being with you every step of
the way until you get the score that you
need all you have to do is just look
down in the description just click that
and you can sign up if you have any
questions about the VIP course always
feel free to get in touch with us we
answer 100% of the questions that we get
hope that you become a VIP if not enjoy
the rest of this free video can I say
everyone um I mean the government uh see
it's in the government's best interests
to ensure that its best and brightest
receive the best education possible
because they will then contribute to
society so it's in the government's best
interest to do it uh from a charity or a
nonprofit standpoint 100% um I actually
so someone once asked me I I was on like
a like another uh someone once asked me
I was having a discussion and they asked
me you know Craig if secure my
scholarship you know just becomes this
huge company and you you exit someday
you know what are you going to do and
you know my my my ambition at least if I
have the resources uh my ambition in
life is to someday open schools not
university schools at the primary level
or up to the Middle School level and
make it free just for any student to
come and get a great education for free
literally so that's something that I am
passionate about that's also why I work
a 100 hours a week on secure my
scholarship um so I mean if there's a
charity or a nonprofit that's committed
to this cause then 100% um and the third
I guess stakeholder is the universities
themselves I mean let's let's get one
thing straight right universities are
incredibly wealthy institutions you look
at not even your top 20 or top 30 you
look at your top 200 universities in the
US in the UK they have billion doll
endowment funds that are invested into
you know some uh some invested into
government bonds or t- builds or or
whatever it may be uh there are billion
I think Harvard's endowment fund is 40
billion or 50 billion I mean don't quote
me on that but it's it's in that ballark
range that's a lot of money from a un
iversity standpoint as well um I I I
feel like it should just be a part of
their social responsibility to give back
to the community that has given them so
much that's what I think how will third
level education change in the future I
think tary education u university
education is going to get more creative
it's already happening as well but I
mean these like higher education is
something that it will never go through
like a a sudden like shift a lot of
people said after Co everything will be
online physical campuses are done
whatever and that just wasn't to be I
mean even till today we have students
who apply through secure my scholarship
for oncampus classes and and online
classes and 99% of students are applying
for oncampus classes um online just
didn't shake up the industry like
everybody predicted but I think the real
change is in the mode of Education
itself gone are the days where you have
to go to class take notes memorize come
back next week and regurgitate that on a
test or an exam that that that doesn't
work anymore you're not training people
the right way because today if you need
information there's Google there's chat
GPT and probably a lot of other
resources that can't come to mind right
now but information is available at your
fingertips what you need to train people
about or train people for today is how
to utilize this information how well can
you analyze the information in front of
you how well can you use the data that
you have available to you um do you know
where to look how well can you think
through the problem to then break it
down to then find the solution in this
sea of information available on the
internet how well can you do these
things how creatively can you think
through a problem and figure out a
solution these are things that cannot be
replaced very easily by you know chat
GPT or Google or whatever this these are
the skills of the future memorization
and answering questions on an exam is
it's not really required anymore and I
think this this shift is already
happening and will really become more
profound maybe 10 or 15 years from now
well done that's the end of the speaking
test awesome thank you so much so full
disclosure Craig is not one of our
students we've never taught him English
he's never attended any of our a courses
or anything anything like that we want
to be 100% honest with you guys but I
noticed Craig online and he's an Indian
national who I think you will agree has
reached a level in English which is
unbelievable he's easily a b nine uh if
there was anything above a band nine I
think uh Craig would get there also
Craig as he mentioned a few times in the
interview runs a company called secure
my scholarship Isles Advantage has no
affiliation we're not sponsored by them
we won't make any money if you go there
but we thought that it would be a great
opportunity for our audience because a
lot of our audience hopes to go to
university but you might be struggling
financially Craig if you sign up for
secure my scholarship he guarantees is
that correct guarantees and it's
absolutely free absolutely free and he
guarantees to get you know at least
something off a scholarship and could
save you potentially thousands if not
tens of thousands of dollars
uh attending some of the best
universities in the world up to you if
you want to visit there I would
recommend it but as I said we don't make
any money from it but thank you so much
Craig it was great listening to you and
I'm sure people learned a lot from your
performance and I'm hope that some of
them check out your website as well
thank you so much for having me Chris I
really appreciate it thank you so much
for having me and best of luck with your
with your company thank you